<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reads on ANT 6973, Spring 2021</title>
    <link>/read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reads on ANT 6973, Spring 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Color, Saving Output, and Composing Multiple Plots</title>
      <link>/read/color-output-composing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/color-output-composing/</guid>
      <description>Read Making effective use of color
 Wilke, Ch. 4: Color scales Wilke, Ch. 19: Common pitfalls of color use  
Saving plots as image files
 R4DS, Ch. 28.7: Saving your plots Wilke, Ch. 27: Understanding the most commonly used image file formats  
Composing multiple plots
 Wilke, Ch. 21: Multi-panel figures Patchwork: Getting started    Color Resources  Color Brewer: Color advice and a great set of color palettes; r package: RColorBrewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color, Saving Output, and Geospatial Data</title>
      <link>/read/viz-geospatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/viz-geospatial/</guid>
      <description>Read Visualizing Geospatial Data
 Wilke, Ch. 15: Visualizing geospatial data Why all world maps are wrong XKCD Map Projections   Extra Software and R Packages for Geospatial Data To use the powerful spatial functions in R, some extra software will be required. R doesn’t do all the geographic calculations by itself. It relies on some other software that runs behind the scenes. Depending on your computer and how it’s configured, some of you may able to get this working right away, whereas others may need some additional steps as detailed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Import</title>
      <link>/read/data-import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/data-import/</guid>
      <description>Read Organizing Data  &amp;ldquo;Tidy Data&amp;rdquo; by Hadley Wickham.  Don&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention to any R code you encounter, as most of it has now been superseded by newer tidyverse functions. This was Wickham&amp;rsquo;s early &amp;ldquo;tidy tools&amp;rdquo; manifesto; it provided guiding principles and a framework for developing the tidyverse.   Peruse the website &amp;ldquo;Data Organization in Spreadsheets&amp;rdquo;, much of which has been written up in a journal article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation 1: Filter, Select, Arrange, Mutate</title>
      <link>/read/dplyr-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/dplyr-1/</guid>
      <description>Read  R4DS, 5.1&amp;ndash;5.5: Data Transformation: dplyr basic verbs: filter, arrange, select, and mutate.  Optional further reading.  Introduction to dplyr: many code examples Modern Dive, Chapter 4: Data Wrangling: Similar to assigned reading but organized differently. Might be a little easier to follow?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation 2: Grouped Summaries, Filters, and Mutates</title>
      <link>/read/dplyr-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/dplyr-2/</guid>
      <description>Read  R4DS, 5.6&amp;ndash;5.7: Data Transformation: dplyr basic verbs: summarise, group_by, and new ways to use mutate and filter.  Optional further reading (same as last week).  Introduction to dplyr: many code examples Modern Dive, Chapter 4: Data Wrangling: Similar to assigned reading but organized differently. Might be a little easier to follow?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction &amp; Setup</title>
      <link>/read/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/setup/</guid>
      <description>Read   Preface of Healy&amp;rsquo;s Data Visualization.
  Introduction of Wickham&amp;rsquo;s R for Data Science (or &amp;ldquo;R4DS&amp;rdquo;).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Basics and R Markdown</title>
      <link>/read/r-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/r-basics/</guid>
      <description>Read  ModernDive Ch. 1: Getting Started with Data in R (section 1.1 is review, the rest may be more useful)
 Healy Section 2.3: Things to know about R
 Chapter 2 of R Markdown: The Definitive Guide (skip the long video at the end and the example applications)
   Skim  Tidyverse style guide, Ch. 1 and Ch. 2. Consistent style is an important element of communication and collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Basics and R Markdown</title>
      <link>/read/r-basics_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/r-basics_old/</guid>
      <description>Read   ModernDive Ch. 1: Getting Started with Data in R
  Healy Section 2.3: Things to know about R
  Chapter 2 of R Markdown: The Definitive Guide (you can skip the long video at the end and the example applications)
  Tidyverse style guide, Ch. 1 and Ch. 2. Consistent style is an important element of communication and collaboration. SKIM over the sections 1. Files and 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-table Operations: Joins and Set operations</title>
      <link>/read/two-table-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/two-table-operations/</guid>
      <description>Read   Modern Dive, Chapter 4.7: &amp;ldquo;Join Data Frames&amp;rdquo;: A concise overview of join verbs in dplyr.
  R4DS, 13: Relational Data: More detailed, with many examples. Also covers set operations.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization Basics</title>
      <link>/read/viz-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/viz-basics/</guid>
      <description>  Read  Healy, Ch. 1: Look At Data Wilke, Ch. 1: Introduction Wilke, Ch. 2: Visualizing data: Mapping data onto aesthetics Wilke, Ch. 5: Directory of Visualizations   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Amounts and Parts of a Whole</title>
      <link>/read/viz-amounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/viz-amounts/</guid>
      <description>  Read  Wilke, Ch. 6: Visualizing Amounts Wilke, Ch. 10: Visualizing Proportions Wilke, Ch. 11: Visualizing Nested Proportions  
 Kristin Henry (2017) “In Defense of Pie Charts, and Why You Shouldn’t Use Them.” Robert Kosara (2016), “Stacked Bars Are the Worst.” Datawrapper, “What to consider when creating stacked column charts.”    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Distributions and Uncertainty</title>
      <link>/read/viz-distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/viz-distributions/</guid>
      <description>  Read  Wilke, Ch. 7: Visualizing distributions: Histograms and density plots Wilke, Ch. 9: Visualizing many distributions at once Wilke, Ch. 16: Visualizing uncertainty  Popovich and Pearce, “It’s Not Your Imagination. Summers Are Getting Hotter.” Matthew Conlen, “Kernel Density Estimation” Nicole Torres (2010), “Why It’s So Hard for Us to Visualize Uncertainty” Robert Kosara (2017), “Communicating Uncertainty When Lives Are on the Line”   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Relationships and Change Over Time</title>
      <link>/read/viz-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/read/viz-relationships/</guid>
      <description>  Read  Wilke, Ch. 12: Visualizing associations among two or more quantitative variables Wilke, Ch. 13: Visualizing time series and other functions of an independent variable Wilke, Ch. 14: Visualizing trends  Nathan Yau, “11 Ways to Visualize Changes Over Time – A Guide” Keiran Healy, “Two Y-Axes” Stephanie Evergreen, “Two Alternatives to Using a Second Y-Axis”   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
