<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on ANT 6973, Spring 2021</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on ANT 6973, Spring 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Final Project</title>
      <link>/projects/final-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/final-project/</guid>
      <description>Due date: May 05 by the end of the day (11:59:59 pm)Description The final project should essentially look like any of our small projects, but with two key differences:
  You will decide on the data set to use, and I especially encourage you to find and/or use a data set that is related to your thesis topic. If this is not possible, I can help you find a data set on a topic relevant to your interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Project 1: Ape Teeth</title>
      <link>/projects/small-project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/small-project-1/</guid>
      <description>Due date: Mar. 17 by the end of the day (11:59:59 pm)
Introduction In this small project, you will think of conceptual questions to ask of a data set of ape teeth measurements and create plots to answer those questions.
Description of the data
 Download: -  ape_teeth.csv Data source: http://anthropologicaldata.free.fr/  Columns
 Species: ape species the tooth belongs to, including:  Gorilla gorilla (Western gorilla) Pan troglodytes (Common chimpanzee) Pongo pygmaeus (Bornean orangutan)  Site: where specimen is located Specimen: specimen ID number Sex: Male or Female Source: where data come from Tooth: name of tooth (see below).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Project 2</title>
      <link>/projects/small-project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/small-project-2/</guid>
      <description>Due date: Apr. 18 by the end of the day (11:59:59 pm)Introduction In this small project, you will think of conceptual questions to ask of one or more data sets.
Because I think some of you disliked the ape_teeth data set from small project 1, this time I&amp;rsquo;m providing several different data sets that can be used.
All your questions can be from one data set, or you can ask different questions of different data sets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
